<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://cervidaze.me/">
  <title>cervidaze</title>
  <subtitle>a personal repository lovingly created by a writer of many varieties.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://cervidaze.me/rss.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2025-11-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://cervidaze.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>reyn</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>breaking down (my website)</title>
    <content type="html">i was inspired by seeing aid&#39;s recent post where she breaks down the layout of her website and thought i should write one of my own—both to document my code and also to offer troubleshooting to those who may have the same extremely specific coding issues as me.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-11-22-sitebreakdown.html" />
    <updated>2025-11-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-11-22-sitebreakdown.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>i know when fall is here</title>
    <content type="html">this month has been kind to me. my girlfriend and i went to san diego for a much needed respite from our usual obligations. everything was great up until the point where i caught COVID despite taking as many precautions as i could. it&#39;s the first time i caught it in three years, so i guess it wasn&#39;t for nothing. the COVID itself (likely the status variant) was not terribly agonizing, but past experiences with ME/CFS that debilitated me for months has made me terribly afraid of developing long COVID and having ME/CFS flare ups again.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-09-28-iknowwhenfallishere.html" />
    <updated>2025-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-09-28-iknowwhenfallishere.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>digital minimalism and death machines</title>
    <content type="html">my workplace won&#39;t let me die. i&#39;ve experienced four waves of layoffs in the one year and ten months i&#39;ve been here now, and i haven&#39;t been laid off a single time. my coworkers (or i guess former coworkers now) were so happy to leave and finally be able to focus on their creative side projects without distraction now. i wonder what that&#39;s like.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-08-30-digitalminimalism.html" />
    <updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-08-30-digitalminimalism.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title></title>
    <content type="html"></content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/" />
    <updated>2025-07-27T08:22:52Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>on hiatus, change, and grief again</title>
    <content type="html">i&#39;m alive and i have made it to the end of july. i&#39;m about eight weeks post-op from top surgery. my girlfriend and i recently celebrated four years together. my band is recording our first album. lots of things to wait for and lots of things to look forward to.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-07-25-hiatuschangegriefagain.html" />
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-07-25-hiatuschangegriefagain.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>nothing ever happens</title>
    <content type="html">i haven&#39;t been extremely online lately—mostly because my cats get extremely upset when i keep myself in the office for too long. it&#39;s been about half a year since i&#39;ve basically left all social media, and it&#39;s been quiet. i also ran out of online distractions to occupy myself with, which led to me finally jailbreaking both my kindle and my 3DS for fun. i just completed pokemon black 2 at the 72-hour mark, and i have yet to look back.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-04-30-nothing-ever-happens.html" />
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-04-30-nothing-ever-happens.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>boycotts and degoogling</title>
    <content type="html">lately, i&#39;ve been making an effort to remove myself from as many google products as possible. i made the browser switch from chrome to firefox about two years ago, but it wasn&#39;t until i saw a post by ykreborn that i decided to start migrating the rest of my dependencies.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-03-21-boycotts-and-degoogling.html" />
    <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-03-21-boycotts-and-degoogling.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mid-twenties</title>
    <content type="html">i had my friend sign my will and advance directive a few weeks ago. it wasn&#39;t for any particular reason. i just wanted to have them ready in case anything were to suddenly happen and make me unable to speak for myself.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-02-25-mid-twenties.html" />
    <updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-02-25-mid-twenties.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>hello again</title>
    <content type="html">it has been a while since i&#39;ve updated about anything in regards to my life. it would be insane to try to list it all out here since a good six months have elapsed since my last post, but i guess i can still try.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-12-26-hello-again.html" />
    <updated>2024-12-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-12-26-hello-again.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>her hair had just grown back</title>
    <content type="html">I can’t help but mention my mother in everything. I got gingko leaves tattooed on my hip because we had a tree in the front yard when I was younger, and she showed me how to press its leaves in her books. My first tattoo is a mythical deer from the animated Chinese film we watched together when I was a kid. It’s the most Buddhist thing I own. My mom has a mole where the Buddha&#39;s mark is supposed to be. I want to include her in everything.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-06-25-herhair.html" />
    <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-06-25-herhair.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>don&#39;t forget the l-theanine</title>
    <content type="html">Another sleepless night—I switched from melatonin to magnesium, but it can only do so much. It&#39;s 6 am.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-06-02-dontforget.html" />
    <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-06-02-dontforget.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>the difference between rot and decay</title>
    <content type="html">Something I&#39;ve been thinking about recently is how my dad has always been recording home videos of my sister and I. Even now, though the mediums have definitely changed.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-04-09-rotanddecay.html" />
    <updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-04-09-rotanddecay.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>100 milligrams, $10 copay</title>
    <content type="html">I turn 23 in less than a month. I wish I knew what else to say.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-01-26-100milligrams.html" />
    <updated>2024-01-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-01-26-100milligrams.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>it&#39;s a 57 minute drive to the city of hope</title>
    <content type="html">When I visited my mom in the hospital after the surgeon removed her entire reproductive system, she was barely conscious and used whatever strength she had left to ask about my girlfriend&#39;s health. She then told me to leave because she was fine and I should be getting home. Yesterday, she called to tell me that I shouldn&#39;t visit her until I&#39;ve recovered from my cold; she started to ask me for something, but the line kept breaking, and all I could hear next was her suddenly sobbing from the pain she was in. She hung up as quickly as she started crying. I still don&#39;t know what she was pleading for through the phone.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-12-19-57minutes.html" />
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-12-19-57minutes.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>unrelated but it&#39;s the anniversary of my dog&#39;s death</title>
    <content type="html">The sun is setting at 5 pm now, but I didn’t notice until this week because I’ve been waking up at 3 pm these past few days. I optimistically thought that these would be the last few days I sleep and wake up at god-awful times—I officially began my 9 to 5 lifestyle yesterday—but it&#39;s almost 3 am and I am very awake.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-11-14-unrelated.html" />
    <updated>2023-11-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-11-14-unrelated.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>stage four ovaria/complex ptsd</title>
    <content type="html">Our odds have slightly improved. It&#39;s not pancreatic cancer, which is almost always terminal. It&#39;s ovarian, which is less terminal. She has a tumor the size of a chicken’s egg resting in her abdomen, and that cancer has metastasized into her lungs. Apparently, that doesn’t kill someone as much as a tumor the size of an almond in the pancreas.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-10-09-stagefour.html" />
    <updated>2023-10-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-10-09-stagefour.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>they found a three centimeter tumor in her pancreas</title>
    <content type="html">When I was 16 and didn&#39;t know what depressive episodes were, I bought a self-help book titled How to Be Happy (Or at Least Less Sad). I got home from school on the day the book was delivered and found it graffitied in my mom&#39;s handwriting with the words, “Just be happy.” I think there couldn&#39;t be a more accurate way to describe how my mother handles—or doesn&#39;t handle—immense suffering.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-09-21-threecentimetertumor.html" />
    <updated>2023-09-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-09-21-threecentimetertumor.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>on hiatus, change, grief</title>
    <content type="html">This break is taking a bit longer than I’d like. Emails and emails of “Unfortunately, we’re moving on with someone else” and “We hope you continue to keep in touch” have forced me to sit with myself in the uncomfortable and humiliating silence of my one-bedroom apartment—one that we’ve been trying to get out of since May.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-09-10-hiatuschangegrief.html" />
    <updated>2023-09-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-09-10-hiatuschangegrief.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>the smoke stays for a bit</title>
    <content type="html">I allow myself one herbal cigarette per month. I don&amp;apos;t even smoke as a habit&amp;mdash;I just wanted to see if I could do it. I think it takes more discipline to smoke only one cigarette a month than it takes to smoke none at all. I think the real habit that needs to be cut back is my scrutinizing adherence to self-imposed tests of will.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-07-24-smokestays.html" />
    <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-07-24-smokestays.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>post grad sad</title>
    <content type="html">I was hoping that life would be a little calmer by now, but my hopes seem to be a bit crushed for the time being&amp;mdash;my doctor inexplicably denied my Zoloft refill right before I only had a couple days&amp;rsquo; worth left.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-05-28-postgradsad.html" />
    <updated>2023-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-05-28-postgradsad.html</id>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>another start</title>
    <content type="html">OUR STILLNESS was a writing project I began when I was 16 years old in my sophomore year of high school, back when I had too many thoughts to write down and not enough of an audience to read them. I am 22 now, freshly graduated and about to take a hiatus from work and academic projects as I have just graduated from university. I&amp;rsquo;ve made the decision to continue writing for OUR STILLNESS but am hosting it here instead of its previous home on Weebly.</content>
    <link href="https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-05-28-another-start.html" />
    <updated>2023-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2023-05-28-another-start.html</id>
  </entry>
  <item>
    <guid>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-04-30-nothing-ever-happens</guid>
    <title>nothing ever happens</title>
    <description>
      i haven't been online lately—mostly because my cats get extremely upset when i keep myself in the office
      for too long. it's been about half a year since i've basically left all social media, and it's been quiet. i also
      ran out of online distractions to occupy myself with, which led to me finally jailbreaking both my kindle and my
      3DS for fun. i just completed pokemon black 2 at the 72-hour mark, and i have yet to look back.
    </description>
    <link>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-04-30-nothing-ever-happens</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, 30 Apr 2025 14:15:00 +0800
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-03-21-boycotts-and-degoogling.html</guid>
    <title>boycotts and degoogling</title>
    <description>
      lately, i've been making an effort to remove myself from as many google products as possible. i made the browser
      switch from chrome to firefox about two years ago, but it wasn't until i saw a post by ykreborn that i decided to
      start migrating the rest of my dependencies.
    </description>
    <link>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-03-21-boycotts-and-degoogling.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Fri, 21 Mar 2025 14:15:00 +0800
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-02-25-mid-twenties</guid>
    <title>mid-twenties</title>
    <description>
      i had my friend sign my will and advance directive a few weeks ago. it wasn&apos;t for any particular
      reason. i just wanted to have them ready in case anything were to suddenly happen and make me unable to
      speak for myself.
    </description>
    <link>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2025-02-25-mid-twenties</link>
    <pubDate>
      Tue, 25 Feb 2025 14:15:00 +0800
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-12-26-hello-again</guid>
    <title>hello again</title>
    <description>
      it has been a while since i&#x27;ve updated about anything in regards to my life. it would be insane to try to
      list it all out here since a good six months have elapsed since my last post, but i guess i can still try.
    </description>
    <link>https://cervidaze.me/blog/posts/2024-12-26-hello-again</link>
    <pubDate>
      Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:15:00 +0800
    </pubDate>
  </item>
</feed>